Okay, so in this video then we are going
to cover another very important tool and
technique called cost aggregation,
a very important tool and technique.
Now cost aggregation is something that you
guys do all the time, at least those of
you that are involved in cost
management and budgeting, you
just probably didn't realize
there's actually a name for it.
And basically it's, before you can come up
with the overall budget for the project,
you have to know how much the individual
components have your project is going to
cost, how much individual activities are
going to cost, how much work packages are
going to cost, and then you're going to
add them up.
You're going to aggregate them to come up
with the overall cost of the project.
So just as a very simple example,
again, in the subject of building a house,
right, in the theme of building a house,
before a builder can give you an estimate
of, you know, how much is going to cost to
build this house, they're going to
estimate the cost of, for example,
the lumber, how much of the concrete going
to cost, how much of the drywall going to
cost?
What's the cost of the electrical system?
What's the cost of plumbing, the air ducts
and vents, and so on and so forth?
They're going to first estimate the cost
of each of these individual components,
and then aggregate those,
add those all up before
they can come up with the
cost of the overall project.
And that's really exactly what cost
aggregation is.
Now, Cost aggregation
also involves rolling
up each layer of the
work breakdown structure.
All right.
So let's talk about this in a bit more
detail.
So cost aggregation then,
as I said, it's also about
rolling up each layer of the
work breakdown structure.
And here's a very simple example.
And this also is a continuation,
if you like, of bottom-up estimating.
Remember, a bottom-up estimate is a very,
very detailed estimate.
right?
And you're breaking your activity into
little sub-activities.
And then the second
part of that is rolling
up each layer of the
work breakdown structure.
And that's what this example is here.
All right.
So down at the bottom here, we have our
activity estimates.
Cost of each activity.
How much is an activity going to cost?
First, you know, we're down to the
granular level.
How much is each activity going to cost?
And then based on those activities,
We may have identified some risks,
and so we're going to put some money aside
in contingency reserve.
Remember, contingency
reserves are for known
risks, risks that may or may not occur.
I mean, it's a risk, it's an unknown,
it may or may not occur.
But we may put some
money aside in contingency
reserve in case, you
know, in case it occurs.
So anyway, contingency
reserves are going to be
discussed in more detail in
the risk management section.
now based on these activity estimates and
contingency reserve right we're going to
add those up that becomes our work package
estimate remember work packages are made
up of many activities also remember just
as a review the work breakdown structure
goes down as far as the work package and
it's a separate process altogether as part
of schedule management where we're
actually taking each work package and
further breaking it down, further
decomposing it into individual activities.
So the activities themselves are not part
of the work breakdown structure.
The work packages are, but in order to
determine how much is the work package
going to cost, you need to know the cost
of the activities.
All right, so the activity
estimate then plus a contingency
reserves, that becomes
our work package estimate.
Now based on our work packages,
we may have identified some additional
risks, in which case then we're going to
put some money in contingency reserve,
some additional money in contingency
reserve.
Add up all of our work
packages and these contingency
reserves, that becomes
our control account estimate.
Then you basically continue rolling up
each layer of the work breakdown structure
until you get to the very top of
the work breakdown structure,
that first box on the WBS,
and that is the cost baseline.
The cost of that then is the cost
baseline.
Now management then, senior management are
going to add in management reserves and
this now becomes the overall project
budget, right?
Could be called the project budget or the
cost budget.
The overall project budget.
Now, something very, very important to
understand here.
Remember, project managers are responsible
for contingency reserves.
The cost baseline includes contingency
reserves.
Senior management are responsible for
management reserves.
Project managers are not responsible for
So the project manager is responsible for
the cost baseline.
The project manager is not responsible for
the entire project budget.
They're not responsible for the entire
budget that includes the
management reserves.
They are responsible for the cost baseline
that includes the contingency reserve.
So always, always remember that.
And just as another quick
review, remember, there are
three baselines that make up
the project management plan.
Right, you have the scope baseline,
schedule baseline, and the cost baseline.
And this one is the cost baseline.
And the cost baseline then is the,
basically, the approved budget,
the approved project managers budget.
which includes contingency reserves,
but does not include management reserves.
That is very, very important to understand
for the PNP exam.
So this is the basic thing of cost
aggregation.
As I said, it does basically finding
individual or estimating the cost of
individual components, adding those up to
come up with the overall budget,
right, the overall cost or the overall
cost baseline.
Okay.